Subject Files
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Subject Files
2.1.3.6
Marist College
  Box 1537 - Box 1543
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1541 - Box 1544
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1545 - Box 1548
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1549 - Box 1552
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1553 - Box 1556
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  Box 1557
- Subject Files, 2.1.3.6
  - Subject files: Skiing (Alaska), undated; 1 (Box 1557)
    - [Lowell Thomas and two others in Alaska], 1
    - Note: In Alaska, 2
  - Subject files: Skiing (Banff, Alberta, Canada) [includes color photographs], 1977 June; 2 (Box 1557)
    - [Lowell Thomas and another man skiing], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas and another man on the top of a ski slope], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas and another man on the ski lift], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas and other skiiers], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with other skiiers], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas with a group of other skiiers], 6
    - [Skiiers on the mountain], 7
    - [Two men skiing], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas and another man on skis], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas and another man on skis], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas skiing], 11
  - Subject files: Skiing (broadcasting), undated; 3 (Box 1557)
    - Caption: To Mr. Lowell Thomas, Compliments and Best Wishes, C. C. Stafford; Note: Lowell Thomas recently scaled Mount Mansfield, the highest peak in the Green Mountains, on skis, with a temperature at forty below. That night he gave a description of his experience on his regular Sunoco News Broadcast, from the Green Mountain Inn at Stowe, Vermont. Reading from left to right, Joe Fountain, official of the New Haven, Central Vermont and Canadian National Railroads; Lowell Thomas, broadcasting; Bob Isham, Vermont ski authority; and Jacques Charmoz, explorer, famous skier and chief instructor to the Chilean Army; Caption: To Mr. Lowell Thomas; Compliments and Best Wishes [signed] C.C. Stafford, 1
    - Note: Lowell Thomas recently scaled Mount Mansfield, the highest peak in the Green Mountains, on skis, with a temperature at forty below. That night he gave a description of his experience on his regular Sunoco News Broadcast, from the Green Mountain Inn at Stowe, Vermont. Reading from left to right, Joe Fountain, official of the New Haven, Central Vermont and Canadian National Railroads; Lowell Thomas, broadcasting; Bob Isham, Vermont ski authority; and Jacques Charmoz, explorer, famous skier and chief instructor to the Chilean Army; Caption: To Mr. Lowell Thomas; Compliments and Best Wishes [signed] C.C. Stafford, 2
    - This is a clearer print than the one I sent you; Left to right, front row: L.T. Jr., Lady who was McClelland Barclay's No. 1 model at that time. Seated in front, with hands crossed - - Harry Wheeler, today owner of the Greyrocks Inn, and at that time he was rather famous for his dog team racing - - the Val d'Or. Sitting right behind him is Mary Bird Young. Middle row: McClelland Barclay, famous artist, ?, L.T., Mary Ryan in white, Hans Faulkner, Chris Young. Back row: - With glasses (standing), white shirt and black tie, Oscar Landry, CPR station agent at St. Jovite. Seated next to him, eyes half closed, is Tom Wheeler, present owner of Lac Ouimette Inn and the Wheeler Airlines which serves Arctic Canada, the Dew Line and so on. Extreme right, smiling, Joe Ryan; Verso: credit Lowell Thomas; "Ski Down the Years," chapt. TEN - page 193 (top), 3
    - Verso: This is a clearer print than the one I sent you; Left to right, front row: L.T. Jr., Lady who was McClelland Barclay's No. 1 model at that time. Seated in front, with hands crossed - - Harry Wheeler, today owner of the Greyrocks Inn, and at that time he was rather famous for his dog team racing - - the Val d'Or. Sitting right behind him is Mary Bird Young. Middle row: McClelland Barclay, famous artist, ?, L.T., Mary Ryan in white, Hans Faulkner, Chris Young. Back row: - With glasses (standing), white shirt and black tie, Oscar Landry, CPR station agent at St. Jovite. Seated next to him, eyes half closed, is Tom Wheeler, present owner of Lac Ouimette Inn and the Wheeler Airlines which serves Arctic Canada, the Dew Line and so on. Extreme right, smiling, Joe Ryan; Verso: credit Lowell Thomas; "Ski Down the Years," chapt. TEN - page 193 (top), 3-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas on skis with two other men], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas and another man], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas and two men standing outside of the Laurentide Inn], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas with his fellow skiiers], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas and another man skiing], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas making a broadcast while others watch], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas making a broadcast on his skiing trip], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas making a radio broadcast on his skiing trip], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas with members of the Mobile Force], 12
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with a group of people], 13
    - [People sitting at a long dining table], 14
    - [Lowell Thomas making a radio broadcast on CBS], 15
  - Subject files: Skiing (California), undated; 4 (Box 1557)
    - Caption: Mammoth Mountain Inn, Mammoth Lakes, Calif., Photographed by John. M. Stephens; Verso: Mary Young, LT, Gladys Sawyer, 1
    - Verso: Mary Young, LT, Gladys Sawyer, 1-verso
    - Caption: Mammoth Mountain Inn, Mammoth Lakes, Calif., Photographed by John. M. Stephens [Mary Young, LT, Gladys Sawyer], 2
    - Caption: Mammoth Mountain Inn, Mammoth Lakes, Calif., Photographed by John. M. Stephens [Mary Young, LT, Gladys Sawyer], 3
    - [left to right] Emile Alais, [Lowell Thomas] and Otto Lang, 4
    - Note: [left to right] Emile Alais, [Lowell Thomas] and Otto Lang, 5
    - LT + Otto Lang, 6
    - Verso: LT + Otto Lang, 6-verso
    - LT and Otto Lang, 7
    - Note: LT and Otto Lang, 8
    - TV Producer LY + Otto Lang [3 copies], 9
    - Verso: TV Producer LY + Otto Lang, 9-verso
    - [LT and Otto Lang], 10
    - Fair skier who asks for L.T.'s autograph, 11
    - Verso: Fair skier who asks for L.T.'s autograph, 11-verso
    - [sheet of 9 photographs] In the Southern Sierras; Can you wipe off the red marks?, 12
    - Verso: In the Southern Sierras; Can you wipe off the red marks?, 12-verso
  - Subject files: Skiing (Colorado), 1960s; 5 (Box 1557)
    - Note: Presenting cups at Aspen. Among the winners, standing next to LT are Jean-Claude Killy and Billy Kidd with tycoon Ted Ryan looking over their shoulders, 1
    - LT, Jean Claude Killy, Ted Ryan and Billy Kidd [1968], 2
    - Verso: LT, Jean Claude Killy, Ted Ryan and Billy Kidd [1968], 2-verso
    - 1968 Rock Cup; [Jean Claude] Killy and [Billy] Kidd, 3
    - Verso: 1968 Rock Cup; [Jean Claude] Killy and [Billy] Kidd, 3-verso
    - Iselin, Christl [Thalhammer], LT at Aspen, 4
    - Note: Iselin, Christl [Thalhammer], LT at Aspen, 5
  - Subject files: Skiing (glacier skiing, British Columbia), 1972 May; 6 (Box 1557)
    - Shutter Glacier, May 1972, 1
    - Verso: Shutter Glacier, May 1972, 1-verso
    - L.T., J.M.C, Jack Simplot, 2
    - Verso: L.T., J.M.C, Jack Simplot, 2-verso
    - L.T., J.M.C, J.S. [Jack Simplot], 3
    - Verso: L.T., J.M.C, J. S. [Jack Simplot], 3-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with three other skiiers], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas standing on a slope with three skiiers], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas and two other skiiers], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas and friends skiing], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas and two others atop a ski mountain], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas and three other skiing], 9
    - Top of Torey Glacier; Fitzimmons Glacier in background, ok, 10
    - Verso: Top of Torey Glacier; Fitzimmons Glacier in background, ok, 10-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas skiing with three other people], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas standing in skis in front of a helicoptor], 12
    - [Man skiing down a mountain], 13
    - Glacier Skiing in Brit. Columbia, 14
    - Note: Glacier Skiing in Brit. Columbia, 15
    - L.T. - J. S. - H. H., 16
    - Verso: L.T. - J. S. - H. H., 16-verso
    - Shutter Glacier, 17
    - Verso: Shutter Glacier, 17-verso
    - Shutter Glacier, 18
    - Verso: Shutter Glacier, 18-verso
    - Skiing at Whister Mtn May 1972, 19
    - Verso: Skiing at Whister Mtn May 1972, 19-verso
    - Note: Glacier Skiing in BC; Not to use., 20
    - Dick Durrance, first U.S. Olympic ski star and LT "pouring it on," on a mountain in British Columbia, 21
    - Note: Dick Durrance, first U.S. Olympic ski star and LT "pouring it on," on a mountain in British Columbia, 22
    - June 1, 1972; The enclosed was made of me recently when I was doing glacier skiing in British Columbia. It's rather better than the one taken the day we were in the Red Room. As always, we much enjoyed our stay with you at the Clift. Cordially, Lowell, 23
    - Note: Lowell Thomas; Hammersley Hill; Pawling, New York 12564; June 1, 1972; The enclosed was made of me recently when I was doing glacier skiing in British Columbia. It's rather better than the one taken the day we were in the Red Room. As always, we much enjoyed our stay with you at the Clift. Cordially, Lowell, 24
  - Subject files: Skiing (Lake Placid, New York), 1939 - 1961; 7 (Box 1557)
    - Photo by G.C., Feb. 1961 - Mt. Whitney, Lake Placid Club, 1
    - Verso: Photo by G.C., Feb. 1961 - Mt. Whitney, Lake Placid Club, 1-verso
    - George Carroll, Lake Placid Club, Essex Country, New York; Lake Placid Club January 1958, 2
    - Verso: George Carroll, Lake Placid Club, Essex Country, New York; Lake Placid Club January 1958, 2-verso
    - Samuel H. [?], Lowell Thomas, Mt. Whitney, about 1939-40 (?), 3
    - Verso: Samuel H. [?], Lowell Thomas, Mt. Whitney, about 1939-40 (?), 3-verso
    - Skiing at Lake Placid, 4
    - Verso: Skiing at Lake Placid, 4-verso
    - L.T. crowning the king (Walter O'Keefe) and queen at the Winter Sports Carnival at Lake Placid, 5
    - Verso: L.T. crowning the king (Walter O'Keefe) and queen at the Winter Sports Carnival at Lake Placid, 5-verso
    - L.T. and Ellen Mason, Queen of Winter [Winter Sports Carnival at Lake Placid], 6
    - Verso: L.T. and Ellen Mason, Queen of Winter [Winter Sports Carnival at Lake Placid], 6-verso
    - Pierson Studio, Lake Placid, N.Y. [Winter Sports Carnival at Lake Placid], 7
    - Verso: Pierson Studio, Lake Placid, N.Y. [Winter Sports Carnival at Lake Placid], 7-verso
  - Subject files: Skiing (New Hampshire), undated; 8 (Box 1557)
    - Caption: Ski [?] from a most flattened peg-leg [signed] Whitney; Note: Atwood, Mrs. Whitney Bourne, Sheep Lane Locust Valley, N.Y., 11560; Jan. 69, Box 1146 Hobe Sound, Florida; Verso: Eastern Slope Inn, White Mountains, North Conway, New Hampshire; Bray Photo, 1
    - Verso: Eastern Slope Inn, White Mountains, North Conway, New Hampshire, Bray Photo, 1-verso
    - Note: Atwood, Mrs. Whitney Bourne, Sheep Lane Locust Valley, N.Y., 11560; Jan. 69, Box 1146 Hobe Sound, Florida, 2
    - Mt. Washington from Mt. Jefferson; April 25, 1935 (after two weeks of snow storms!); Winston H. Pote Photographer, 124 Maple Street Lynn, Mass., 3
    - Verso: Mt. Washington from Mt. Jefferson; April 25, 1935 (after two weeks of snow storms!); Winston H. Pote Photographer, 124 Maple Street Lynn, Mass., 3-verso
    - Mike Feuersinger (Austrian pro) on Cannon Mtn, N.H., 4
    - Verso: Mike Feuersinger (Austrian pro) on Cannon Mtn, N.H., 4-verso
    - [Kurt Thalhammer] Caption: Peckett's Franconia, N.H.; Verso: Photo by Roger L. Moore Note: Doubleday & Co., Inc. 277 Park Ave. New York 22, N.Y.; Illustrations for Adventures with the New Guinea Headhunters; Date: 2/17/65, 5
    - Verso: Photo by Roger L. Moore Note: Doubleday & Co., Inc. 277 Park Ave. New York 22, N.Y., 5-verso
    - [Kurt Thalhammer] Caption: Peckett's Franconia, N.H.; Verso: Photo by Roger L. Moore Note: Doubleday & Co., Inc. 277 Park Ave. New York 22, N.Y.; Illustrations for Adventures with the New Guinea Headhunters; Date: 2/17/65, 6
    - Verso: Photo by Roger L. Moore Note: Doubleday & Co., Inc. 277 Park Ave. New York 22, N.Y., 6-verso
    - Note: Illustrations for Adventures with the New Guinea Headhunters; Date: 2/17/65, 7
    - Bob Duncan, Photographer, North Conway, N.H., 8
    - Verso: Bob Duncan, Photographer, North Conway, N.H., 8-verso
    - Bob Duncan, Photographer, North Conway, N.H., 9
    - Verso: Bob Duncan, Photographer, North Conway, N.H., 9-verso
    - J. Larson, NBC NY, 10
    - Verso: J. Larson, NBC NY, 10-verso
    - Chilean Ski Team, North Conway, N.H.; 1941; 2nd running Harvey Dew Gibson Race, Cranmore Mt., No. Conway N.H.; The chap in the middle with the white gloves and dark sweater is Julio Zegers who broke his legs, both of them. The man second from the right is the captain, "Canuto," taught by Jacques Charmoz.; Photograph by Noel T. Wellman, Kearsarge, N.H., 11
    - Verso: Chilean Ski Team, North Conway, N.H.; 1941; 2nd running Harvey Dew Gibson Race, Cranmore Mt., No. Conway N.H.; The chap in the middle with the white gloves and dark sweater is Julio Zegers who broke his legs, both of them. The man second from the right is the captain, "Canuto," taught by Jacques Charmoz.; Photograph by Noel T. Wellman, Kearsarge, N.H., 11-verso
    - Eastern Slope Inn, White Mountains, North Conway, New Hampshire, Bray Photo; ski, 12
    - Verso: Eastern Slope Inn, White Mountains, North Conway, New Hampshire, Bray Photo; ski, 12-verso
    - Caption: Lowell, My congradulations go with your gold pin! Hammes[?] [illegible] 1941; Verso: Eastern Slope Inn, White Mountains, North Conway, New Hampshire, Bray Photo; ski, 13
    - Verso: Eastern Slope Inn, White Mountains, North Conway, New Hampshire, Bray Photo; ski, 13-verso
  - Subject files: Skiing (photographs for publication), undated; 9 (Box 1557)
    - [Letter from Lowell Thomas to Steve concerning skiing photographs, all notes in folder taken from letter], [PDF], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas] with his long-time friend Frank Elkins who wrote for the New York Times, 2
    - Note: [Lowell Thomas] with his long-time friend Frank Elkins who wrote for the New York Times, 3
    - An early ski picture. I'm sure it was taken somewhere in the East cause I have pictures that same day with the Buchmayr triplets, 4
    - Note: An early ski picture. I'm sure it was taken somewhere in the East cause I have pictures that same day with the Buchmayr triplets, 5
    - At the Harriman Cottage in Sun Valley with Wendell Corey and Stewart Granger. I believe the two in the background were director and cameraman for MGM. They were doing a picture on location at S. V. [Sun Valley]; Verso: Sun Valley; F. Wendell Corey, Stewart Granger, B. Andrew Martin, head cameraman, dir. Ben Hur [1951], 6
    - Verso: Sun Valley; F. Wendell Corey, Stewart Granger, B. Andrew Martin, head cameraman, dir. Ben Hur [1951], 6-verso
    - Note: At the Harriman Cottage in Sun Valley with Wendell Corey and Stewart Granger. I believe the two in the background were director and cameraman for MGM. They were doing a picture on location at S. V. [Sun Valley], 7
    - With a ski group sitting around either before or after a broadcast at the Harriman Cottage; Verso: Duplicate in Winter shorts scrapbook, 8
    - Verso: Duplicate in Winter shorts scrapbook, 8-verso
    - Note: With a ski group sitting around either before or after a broadcast at the Harriman Cottage, 9
    - With Toni Matt on a local hill not too far away from home, 10
    - Note: With Toni Matt on a local hill not too far away from home, 11
    - With Gretchen Fraser and Otto Lang, 12
    - Note: With Gretchen Fraser and Otto Lang, 13
    - With Alf Engen, Norman Dyhrenfurth and Peter Gabriel; Verso: Alf E - Norm Dyrn - LT + Peter Gabriel, 14
    - Verso: Alf E - Norm Dyrn - LT + Peter Gabriel, 14-verso
    - Note: With Alf Engen, Norman Dyhrenfurth and Peter Gabriel, 15
    - Caption: LT - Alta, Utah; Just a pix of LT - I don't know the location, 16
    - Note: Just a pix of LT - I don't know the location, 17
    - His first encounter with skis - note length and one pole. During World War I in Italy, 18
    - Note: His first encounter with skis - note length and one pole. During World War I in Italy, 19
    - LT - Blanche (Christy Hill), LT Jr., Gretchen Fraser, Jack Simplot, (Mrs. Engen-I think) and Alf [Engen], 20
    - Note: LT - Blanche (Christy Hill), LT Jr., Gretchen Fraser, Jack Simplot, (Mrs. Engen-I think) and Alf [Engen], 21
    - [Lowell Thomas] with Alf Engen, 22
    - Note: [Lowell Thomas] with Alf Engen, 23
    - [Lowell Thomas] with Stein Ericksen [Eriksen] in his [Lowell Thomas's] early eighties, 24
    - Verso: Hack Miller photo 1973-1892=age 81, 24-verso
    - Note: [Lowell Thomas] with Stein Ericksen [Eriksen] in his [Lowell Thomas's] early eighties, 25
  - Subject files: Skiing (reception), 1970s; 10 (Box 1557)
    - Toni - H Klein; Verso: Photograph by Margaret Durrance, photo credit, 1
    - Note: Toni - H Klein; Verso: Photograph by Margaret Durrance, photo credit, 2
    - Herb Klein - Representing Pres. Nixon, 3
    - Verso: Herb Klein - Representing Pres. Nixon, 3-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas putting on a crown at a skiing reception], 4
    - [Lowel Thomas holding a crown with four other men], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with two other men wearing a crown], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas giving a speech at a skiing reception], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas delivering a speech at a skiing reception], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking at a skiing reception], 9
    - [Man speaking at a skiing reception], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas receiving an applause at a skiing reception], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to a man at a skiing reception], 12
  - Subject files: Skiing (ski ball at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel), 1968 October 23; 11 (Box 1557)
    - Chris Igaya and wife, John Clair, Hans Kraus and wife, Madi; Photograph by Al Levine, Delmonico's Hotel, 502 Park Avenue New York 22, Plaza 8-2478, Eldorado 5-2500, 1
    - Verso: Chris Igaya and wife, John Clair, Hans Kraus and wife, Madi; Photograph by Al Levine, Delmonico's Hotel, 502 Park Avenue New York 22, Plaza 8-2478, Eldorado 5-2500, 1-verso
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with others at the ski ball at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with others at the ski ball at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas receiving applause at the ski ball at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to a woman at the ski ball at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas and a woman talking at the ski ball at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas making a speech at the ski ball at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking at the ski ball at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 8
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking at the ski ball], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas delivering a speech at the ski ball], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas and others at the ski ball at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 11
  - Subject files: Skiing (ski ball at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel), 1968 October 23; 12 (Box 1557)
    - [Lowell Thomas shaking hands with a man at the ski ball], 1
    - [Lowell Thomas talking with a man and a woman at the ski ball], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with guests at the ski ball], 3
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with three others at the ski ball], [4 copies], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man at the ski ball at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas sitting with a woman at the ski ball], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with a woman at the ski ball], 7
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with a man and a woman at the ski ball], 8
    - [Guests at the ski ball held at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas speaking with two guests at the ski ball], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas talking to guests at the ski ball], 11
    - [Lowell Thomas standing with two guests at the ski ball], 12
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man at the ski ball at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel], 13
    - [Lowell Thomas and two others at the ski ball], 14
    - [Two men talking at the ski ball], 15
    - [Lowell Thomas chatting with guests at the ski ball], 16
    - [Lowell Thomas and two people at the ski ball], 17
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man at the ski ball], 18
    - [Lowell Thomas with three guests at the ski ball], 19
    - [Lowell Thomas and a man holding skis at the ski ball], 20
    - [Lowell Thomas at the ski ball], 21
    - [Lowell Thomas Jr. (?) at the ski ball], 22
    - Caption: Hi Fran, How wonderful to see you again! [illegible] 10/23/68, 23
  - Subject files: Skiing (ski ball at the Waldorf Astoria Hotel) [contact sheets], 1968 October 23; 13 (Box 1557)
    - [sheet of 12 photographs], 1
    - [sheet of 12 photographs], 2
    - [sheet of 12 photographs], 3
    - [sheet of 12 photographs] Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 4
    - Verso: Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 4-verso
    - *Please use number at top of photograph; Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 5
    - Verso: *Please use number at top of photograph; Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 5-verso
    - [sheet of 12 photographs] Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 6
    - Verso: Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 6-verso
    - [sheet of 12 photographs] Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 7
    - Verso: Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 7-verso
    - [sheet of 12 photographs] Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 8
    - Verso: Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 8-verso
    - [sheet of 12 photographs] Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 9
    - Verso: Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 9-verso
    - [sheet of 12 photographs] Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 10
    - Verso: Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 10-verso
    - [sheet of 12 photographs] Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 11
    - Verso: Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 11-verso
    - [sheet of 12 photographs] Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 12
    - Verso: Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 12-verso
    - [sheet of 12 photographs] Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 13
    - Verso: Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 13-verso
    - [sheet of 12 photographs] Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 14
    - Verso: Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 14-verso
    - [sheet of 12 photographs] Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 15
    - Verso: Ski Ball, Waldorf, 10.23.68, 15-verso
  - Subject files: Skiing (ski tow) [Cranmore Mountain Skimobile], circa 1930s; 14 (Box 1557)
    - [Thomas and others riding Cranmore Mountain Skimobile], 1
    - [Thomas and others riding Cranmore Mountain Skimobile], 2
    - [Thomas and others riding Cranmore Mountain Skimobile], 3
    - [Thomas and others riding Cranmore Mountain Skimobile], 4
    - [Thomas and others riding Cranmore Mountain Skimobile], 5
  - Subject files: Skiing (ski trophy in honor of Vic Constant), undated; 15 (Box 1557)
    - [PDF] Note: I've been going through some thousands of pictures, selecting illustrations for the second volume of my autobiography. I gave this trophy in honor of Captain Vic Constant, coach of the West Point ski team back in the late thirties or early forties. Vic was killed when he was making a preliminary run down the Taft Trail in New Hampshire. It was the day before he was to have raced in the Nationals. He was a friend of mine, and much admired by all of us who were active in skiing at the time; Sincerely, Lowell Thomas; To Athletic Director of West Point, West Point, Madeline Salvani c.o Athletic Director U.S. Military Academy West Point, New York; 914-938-3303 (Lt. Gen. Sidney Berry) Captain McPhail - 938-4011, Maj. Campbell, Captain Hansen, 1
    - [Lowell Thomas holding skiing trophy ], [2 copies], 2
    - [Lowell Thomas standing next to skiing trophy], [7 copies], 3
  - Subject files: Skiing (Strawberry Hill), undated; 16 (Box 1557)
    - Note: Put in envelope to show Douglas and Fortenberry [2 contain items 16.2-16.9], 1
    - Note: Strawberry Hill, 2
    - [Man flying off a ski jump], 3
    - [Man looking down a ski slope], 4
    - [Lowell Thomas in a crowd of people ouside a wooden house], 5
    - [Lowell Thomas and others outside a wooden house], 6
    - [Lowell Thomas watching a man go off a ski jump], 7
    - [Man going off a ski jump], 8
    - [Man on skis going off a jump], 9
    - [Lowell Thomas carrying his skis], 10
    - [Lowell Thomas watching a man go off a ski jump], 11